

Website plamen-k.github.io

Email p.kolev22@gmail.com

Github https://github.com/plamen-k

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/plamen-kolev-465915a7

#### **ABOUT**

My name is Plamen Kolev and I am a Newcastle, England based developer specializing in web application development, system automation and web app deployment. I enjoy playing with emerging technologies and stay up to date with thech trends.

In the past years, I have gained knowledge in Perl, Bash, Unix-based operating systems, python for web development and PHP.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer Intern, Intel Corporation

August 2015 - September 2016

Worked on high-perormance, security projects.

Created automated tests using bash, Perl and inhouse tools. Developed scripts to automate product integration and deployment in a large, multi-national team

Interviewer, Populus Data Solutions

April 2014 - June 2015

Conducted national studies across Britain on sociopolitical issues

Lead Graphic Designer, Ivesto Company
September 2012 - June 2013

Worked full time as a website manager and designer where I had the opportunity to improve the user experience and maintain the two websites of the company.

#### **PROJECTS**

Neven Body care

5 August - 28 August 2016

Created a website for the neven brand

Secure Coding Presentation

5 May 2016

### Lloyds Banking

September 2014 - March 2015

Developed and designed a website with restful API that hooks to an Android application for the british bank Lloyds. The product was produced as part of a team.

HackNE Hackathon

31 October 2014

Co-organized a hackathon in the North East, United Kingdom backed by Major League Hacking EU.

Created the website for the event, PR and print design materials.

# **PAConsulting**

12 February 2014

Developed an environmental friendly hardware & software solution with the Raspberry Pi that involves predictive light automation and controll.

## **EDUCATION**

BSc. Computer Science, Newcastle University

September 2013 - Present

Object-oriented programing, design & development of software. Web design & construction: delivery and consumption of web content, database technologies.

Computer Architecture: Parallel Computer

**Architectures** 

Low-level programing. Software Engineering - principles and lifecycle, scalability and maintnance. Team projects, working as part of a group.

Webloz

18 April 2012

Webloz -national competition for web development finalist